thearbiter.net 2010-06-17

# ArbiterSports.com - Privacy Statement

### Privacy Policy

Arbiter, LLC ("ArbiterSports") has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. This document describes ArbiterSport's practices with respect to the collection of user information from this website and the use and disclosure of such information. This document only applies to the ArbiterSports site ArbiterSports.com and our Arbiter Online URL and does not address the privacy of information we obtain from places other than our website. In addition, other sites on the web (including those we link to) have their own privacy policies and practices. In all cases we encourage you to ask questions and to provide data only to sites whose practices and personnel you trust.

**Information collected and how it's used**

We do not collect any personally identifying information about you unless you or the organization to which you belong voluntarily submits such information to us. The information that we have about you is sensitive information and we are diligent in our efforts to protect it. Depending on your group and the particular Arbiter features they use, that information may include your name, address, phone numbers, email address, social security number, and date of birth. Your social security number and personal information may be distributed by an admin to those responsible for your compensation and for other similar purposes. Since ArbiterSports cannot control how your assigner and others protect your social security number and other personal information, ArbiterSports cannot and does not ensure or warrant the security or privacy of any of your personal information. Some or all of this information may be necessary for the application to perform some function correctly or for providing information required or requested by government agencies. When requesting technical support you may be asked to provide some personal information that we deem necessary to identify who you are and to associate you with one of our user groups. An ArbiterSports sales representative may contact you to determine if you are interested in other ArbiterSports products or services. Such representative may ask you if you would like to receive additional information on our products and services. If you are not interested, please advise the ArbiterSports sales representative accordingly, and you will not be contacted again by ArbiterSports. From time to time, we may also notify you about new products and services we are offering. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information.

ArbiterSports collects user information to make it easier and more efficient for you to use our site. We collect non-personally identifying information about you in a number of ways, including tracking your activities through your IP address or most-recently-visited URL or through "cookies". (For more information on IP addresses or Cookies, please see the appropriate sections below). We may eventually use such information to tailor the content, services and advertising on our websites to your current and future needs. Non-personally identifying information might include the type of browser you use, the type of computer, the operating system, the Internet service provider and other similar information. We use such information in the aggregate to understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site. This way we know which areas of our site are the most commonly used, which areas need improvement, and what technologies are being used so that we may continually improve our site.

In addition, in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture or other transfer or disposition of some or all of the assets of the ArbiterSports Corporation or its affiliated entities to third party successors in interest, you acknowledge and agree that we can accordingly assign, sell, license or transfer any information, including personally identifying information, that our visitors have provided to us to such third parties.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that are written to your computer. They make our website easier for you to use because they save your preferences while you're at our site (although we do not save your passwords in cookies). Cookies contain information that the server computer "knew" in the first place, and are designed to only be read by the serving domain that placed them. Cookies are a standard part of Internet use and allow server computers to recognize your computer's browser when you return to our site. For example, a cookie may retain information regarding items that remain in your shopping cart when you leave our site so that you don't have to start your shopping again from scratch when you return. The non-personally identifying information that we track with cookies is anonymous and is not used to identify, or lead us back to, any particular visitor.

Most browsers are set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you elect not to accept cookies, please note that some parts of the ArbiterSports site, such as shopping, contests or games, may not function properly, or at all, or may be considerably slower.

**IP Address**

An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're using the WorldWideWeb. Web servers - the big computers that "serve up" web pages - automatically identify your computer by its IP address.

We may also use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer our site, track users' movements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not normally linked to personally identifying information. This means that a visitor's session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us.

**Disclosure of Information**

As part of the registration process, ArbiterSports may provide you with the option of receiving information from third parties. If you select this option, ArbiterSports will transfer your contact information to third parties. If you do not want to receive information from third parties in the future, call the ArbiterSports Customer Support Department at 801-576-9436. (Please note that ArbiterSports is not responsible for removing your information from third party lists or entities with which you have previously authorized ArbiterSports to share your information.) You will need to contact those third parties directly to request removal from their lists. Unless we tell you otherwise, we do not sell or rent your personally identifying information to any third parties. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.

We may sell and rent aggregated information about our users generally to our advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties. We also may produce aggregated reports for advertisers identifying, for example, the number of users that visit our site or different areas of our site, the number of users that clicked on an advertisement or the number of users that read a particular article. Aggregate information refers to information that cannot be directly linked to a specific individual. For example, we may know that 25,000 people visited our site today, or that 75% of those visitors were women but we don't know their names. We may use aggregate information to customize our content and advertising, or to deliver a better experience for our visitors. Aggregated information does not include personally identifying information about you or your use of our site.

Disclosure of Information in Special Circumstances

ArbiterSports reserves the right to disclose information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating ArbiterSports's Terms of Use or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) ArbiterSports's rights or property, other ArbiterSports users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. ArbiterSports may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service and improve our products and services.

**Opt out**

You can help ArbiterSports maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your address, phone number or email address. Users are given the opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. For example, our download form has an opt-in option so users who download the trial software from us but don't want to receive any marketing materials. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter may remove their name from the distribution list at any time by contacting us at 801-576-9436. If you have subscribed under more than one email address, you will need to unsubscribe for each of your email addresses.

Links to other Sites

Users will find advertising or other content on our site that links to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. In many cases, the links represent cooperative projects or are mutual links established with persons or entities connected with our site. We do not control the content or links that appear on these third party sites. In addition, these third party sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These third party sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies, or no policy at all. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party site or service before providing any of them with your personal information.

**Minors**

ArbiterSports's site is not designed for children age 13 or younger and therefore does not collect or want any personally identifying information from children.

**Security**

Protecting your privacy and your information is a priority at ArbiterSports. We do not rent or sell the personal financial information you provide to us. We use industry-standard methods to protect your personally identifying information from unauthorized access. Among other techniques, we usually store such information on a computer behind a "firewall" in a secure location, and we take measures to restrict the number of employees internally who can access such data. When our registration or order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number), that information is encrypted and protected using industry-standard encryption technology - 128-bit encryption SSL (Secure Socket Layers). In addition, as an added security measure, if you use a credit card to make a purchase on our site, an ArbiterSports representative may call you to verify the transaction.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also take steps to protect user information off-line. Access to all of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifying information. Furthermore, employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy policies and practices. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifying information are kept in a secure environment.

Of course, there is no such thing as "perfect security" on the Internet and no data transmission can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, ArbiterSports cannot and does not ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or put on our site, and you do so at your own risk.

**Passwords**

Your ArbiterSports account information is password protected so that only you are authorized to access this personal information. We strongly recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. ArbiterSports will not ask for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email.

**Amendments**

We may change this policy from time to time to address new issues and reflect changes on our site. We will post those changes here (and such changes become effective upon posting) so that you will know what information we collect, how we might use that information, and whether we disclose that information to anyone. Please refer back to this policy regularly.

Your Acceptance of these Terms

By accessing and using the ArbiterSports site, you signify your agreement to and acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not access or use our site. Your continued use of the ArbiterSports site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes.

**Additional Information**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact our Customer Support Department by phone 801-576-9436 or by email at support@arbitersports.com.

Last updated July 7, 2009.  
Copyright © 2003 - 2009 Arbiter, LLC. All rights reserved.
